Victor Raul Cardenas Gil

<u>LinkedIn: victor-cardenas-g</u> <u>GitHub: VictorCard</u>enasG

Guadalajara, México +52 33 27060143 victor.cardenas.gil1@gmail.com

Education

Master's Degree in Computer **Science (GPA 98/100)**

August 2023 - Present **ITESO** Guadalajara, México

Google User Experience Professional Certificate

November 2021 - April 2022

Bachelor's Degree in Architecture (GPA 96/100)

August 2015 - May 2021 **ITESO** Guadalajara, México

International Experience

Technische Universität Braunschweig

(ISEP Scholarship winner)

March - August 2019 Braunschweig, Germany

Université Laval (ELAP Scholarship winner)

August - September 2019 Québec, Canada

Languages

Spanish: Native

English: Advanced TOEFL 643 pts

French: Advanced

DELF B2

German: Intermediate

B1.2

Tools



Python

















Working Experience

Data Scientist at Melvin Pay Fintech Startup

May 2024 - Present

- Developed a rule-based fraud detection system based on customer behavior analysis. Results | 100% fraudulent rejection rate and 92% of valid applicants pre-approval without manual or AI model review.
- Designed and implemented a modular feature extraction and decision pipeline. Results | 79% of loan requests automation with 0% fraudulent approvals.
- Conducted exploratory data analysis, feature engineering and unit testing. SQL usage for data querying. Actively contributed to SCRUM processes and presented insights to stakeholders.
- Tools Used: Python (Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Scikit-Learn), MySQL, SQL, GitHub, Jira

BIM Manager and Designer at Estudio 3.14

May 2021 - October 2023

Directed BIM processes and led cross-functional teams. Results | Reduced architectural plan delivery time by 30% through streamlined digital workflows.

UX|UI Designer for MA Octavio Navarro Art Appraiser (Freelance Project)

May 2022 - July 2022

- Desktop and mobile site design from concept to completion, incorporating user research and iterative prototyping to enhance usability.
- Tools Used: Figma, Adobe Photoshop, JavaScript, CSS, HTML

Personal Projects

Facial Expression Recognition for UX Analysis (Master's Thesis Project) Current Results | 82% Precision on Test Dataset

Tools Used: Python (PyTorch, Timm, OpenCV, Scikit-Learn)

Sports Sponsor Recommendation System using NoSQL

Tools Used: Python, Neo4j, MongoDB, AWS EC2

About Me

With five years of experience in the design field, I've honed soft skills like leadership, adaptability, and teamwork-qualities that transcend industries. Having worked in roles from intern to manager, I understand what it takes to inspire teams at different levels and thrive on learning quickly.

I believe teamwork and purposeful design can drive lasting change.